08 - Non-Proliferation Treaty
NATO Archives Online
- Political Affairs Subject File on Proliferation, 1966-1968; Volume 2; 160 Items; Subject File - Non-Proliferation Treaty
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Monday, 2nd October, 1967, at 10.15 a.m., 1967-10-23; 114 - C-R(67)41; 19 pages
  - Recent Developments concerning Article III of the Draft Non-Proliferation Treaty, 1967-10-05; 115 - RS(67)118; 4 pages
  - US Aide Memoire, 1967-10-05; 116 - US Aide Memoire; 13 pages
  - Recent Developments concerning Article III of the Draft Non-Proliferation Treaty, 1967-10-06; 117 - DPA(67)211; 1 page
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 10th October, 1967, at 10.15 a.m., 1967-11-08; 118 - C-R(67)42; 24 pages
  - PROPOSED MEXICAN CHANGES TO NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY, 1967-10-12; 119 - Proposed Change to NPT; 6 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels 39, on Wednesday, 18th October, 1967 at 9.30 a.m., 1967-10-30; 120 - C-R(67)43; 6 pages
  - Initiatives in Euratom concerning the Non-Prollferation Treaty, 1967-10-20; 121 - RS(67)120; 2 pages
  - Draft Non-Prollferation Treaty, 1967-10-25; 122 - 20-10-5_3512_67; 5 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Wednesday, 25th October, 1967 at 10.15 a.m., 1967-11-06; 123 - C-R(67)44; 9 pages
  - Five EURATOM Principles, 1967-10-31; 124 - 20-10-5_3699_67; 1 page
  - Draft Non-Prollferation Treaty, 1967-10-31; 125 - 20-10-5_3708_67; 4 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Tuesday, 31st October, 1967 at 10.15 a.m., 1967-11-14; 126 - C-R(67)45; 7 pages
  - NPT SECURITY ASSURANCES - DRAFT UN RESOLUTION, 1967-11-02; 127 - NPT Security Resolution; 4 pages
  - Statement, by Ambassador Cleveland on NPT for NAC November 9, 1967-11-09; 128 - Cleveland Statement 09-11-67; 4 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Thursday, 9th November, 1967 at 10.15 a.m., 1967-11-24; 129 - C-R(67)46; 16 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Thursday, 14th November, 1967 at 11.30 a.m., 1967-11-23; 130 - C-R(67)47; 12 pages
  - THREE ALTERNATIVES FOR FIRST SENTENCE OF ARTICLE III, 1967-11-23; 131 - Alternatives for Art.111; 6 pages
  - U.S. PAPER ON NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY OF 23rd NOVEMBER, 1967, 1967-11-24; 132 - RS(67)134; 3 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Friday, 24th November, 1967 at 5.30 p.m., 1967-12-13; 133 - C-R(67)48; 10 pages
  - Statement on NPT by Ambassador Cleveland in NAC, November 24, 1967-11-27; 134 - US Statement in NAC; 7 pages
  - Negotiations on the Non-Prollferation Treaty and further procedure, 1967-11-29; 135 - RS(67)135; 3 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Thursday, 30th November, 1967 at 10.15 a.m., 1967-12-08; 136 - C-R(67)49; 18 pages
  - CANADIAN COMMENTS MADE IN NAC NOVEMBER 30 ON THE MEMORANDUM CIRCULATED BY THE UNITED STATES DELEGATION NOVEMBER 23 ON THE PROGRESS OF NEGOTIATIONS ON THE NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY, 1967-12-01; 137 - CA Comments; 4 pages
  - Safeguards in the Non-Proliferation Treaty, 1967-11-30; 138 - UK Comments; 4 pages
  - Statement on NPT by Ambassador Cleveland in NAC, November 30, 1967-12-04; 139 - US Delegation; 5 pages
  - Remarks by President Johnson December 2, 1967 On the 25th Anniversary of Atomic Energy, 1967-12-04; 140 - US Delegation 04-12-67; 5 pages
  - Mr. Mulley’s statement on safeguards, 1967-12-04; 141 - UK Delegation Letter 04-12-67; 2 pages
  - Draft Non-Prollferation Treaty, 1967-12-05; 142 - DPA(67)244; 5 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Wednesday, 6th December, 1967 at 10.15 a.m., 1968-01-22; 143 - C-R(67)53; 17 pages
  - Non-Prollferation Treaty Article III progress report, 1967-12-14; 144 - US Delegation Letter 14-12-67; 3 pages
  - NPT Statement by Ambassador Campbell at December 19 Council Meeting on the Proposed Withdrawal and Duration Article, 1967-12-21; 145 - Campbell Statement; 3 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Wednesday, 19th December, 1967 at 11 a.m., 1968-01-19; 146 - C-R(67)54; 17 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Wednesday, 17th January, 1968 at 10.15 a.m., 1968-01-30; 148 - C-R(68)2; 21 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Thursday, 18th January, 1968 at 12 a.m., 1968-02-01; 150 - C-R(68)3; 7 pages
  - US DRAFT TREATY ON THE NON-PROLIFERATION OF NUCLEAR WEAPONS, 1968-01-19; 152 - Draft Text of NPT; 6 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Tuesday, 23rd January, 1968 at 4 p.m., 1968-02-06; 154 - C-R(68)4; 5 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Wednesday, 31rd January, 1968 at 10.15 a.m., 1968-02-19; 156 - C-R(68)7; 16 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Wednesday, 7th February, 1968 at 10.15 a.m., 1968-02-15; 158 - C-R(68)8; 5 pages
  - NEW U.S./SOVIET DRAFT FOR THE NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY - PROBLEMS OF SUBSTANCE AND PROCEDURE, 1968-02-13; 160 - RS(68)10; 7 pages
  - NEW U.S./SOVIET DRAFT FOR THE NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY - PROBLEMS OF SUBSTANCE AND PROCEDURE, 1968-02-13; 161 - DPA(68)32; 1 page
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Wednesday, 14th February, 1968 at 4 p.m., 1968-02-22; 162 - C-R(68)9; 15 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Wednesday, 21th February, 1968 at 10.15 a.m., 1968-03-04; 164 - C-R(68)10; 12 pages
  - Text of a statement by Ambassador Grewe on the subject of NPT in the NATO Council Meeting on 28 February1968, 1968-03-05; 166 - 20-10-5_68; 2 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Wednesday, 28th February, 1968 at 10.15 a.m., 1968-03-15; 167 - C-R(68)11; 21 pages
  - Statement by Mr. William Cargo in NAC on the NPT February 2°, 1968-02-28; 169 - Statement by Mr. Cargo; 2 pages
  - MEMORANDUM OF 6 MARCH 1968 CONCERNING THE DRAFT OF A NUCLEAR NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY, 1968-03-06; 170 - 20-10-5_68 VS-NfD; 7 pages
  - Statement by Ambassador Cleveland on the Non-Proliferation Treaty in NAC, March 6, 1963, 1968-03-06; 171 - Cleveland Statement 06-03-68; 4 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Wednesday, 6th March, 1968 at 10.15 a.m., 1968-03-22; 173 - C-R(68)12; 25 pages
  - Draft Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons, 1968-03-11; 175 - Draft NPT; 7 pages
  - Statement by Minister Cargo on the NPT in NAC, 1968-03-13; 176 - Statement by Mr. Cargo; 2 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Wednesday, 13th March, 1968 at 10.15 a.m. and 4.30 p.m., 1968-03-02; 177 - C-R(68)13; 17 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Wednesday, 20th March, 1968 at 10.15 a.m., 1968-04-05; 179 - C-R(68)14; 9 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Wednesday, 10th April, 1968 at 10.15 a.m., 1968-04-25; 182 - C-R(68)18; 15 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, on Wednesday, 24th April, 1968 at 10.15 a.m., 1968-05-07; 184 - C-R(68)19; 19 pages
  - Political Committee Meeting on Tuesday 30th April, 1968, 1968-05-02; 187 - AC-119-R(68)26; 4 pages
  - Political Committee Meeting on Tuesday 30th April, 1968, 1968-05-14; 188 - AC-119-R(68)27; 2 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, 39, on Wednesday, 3th May, 1968 at 10 a.m., 1968-05-21; 189 - C-R(68)22; 15 pages
  - Aide Mémoire to the Government of Australia on the Non-Proliferation Treaty, 1968-05-17; 191 - Aide Memoire; 5 pages
  - NATO INITIATIVES CONCERNING THE NPT, 1968-05-29; 192 - RS(68)34; 2 pages
  - NATO INITIATIVES CONCERNING THE NPT, 1968-05-29; 193 - DPA(68)105; 1 page
  - Text of Revised UNGA Resolution Endorsing the Non-Proliferation Treaty, 1968-05-29; 194 - Text of Revised UNGA Resolution; 4 pages
  - Draft Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons, 1968-05-31; 195 - Draft NPT; 8 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, 39, on Friday, 7th June, 1968 at 10.15 a.m., 1968-07-15; 196 - C-R(68)28; 10 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the NATO Headquarters, Brussels, 39, on Thursday, 20th June, 1968 at 10.15 a.m., 1968-07-12; 198 - C-R(68)33; 12 pages
  - NPT and the security assurances inherent in the North Atlantic Treaty, 1968-06-28; 200 - US Delegation Letter 28-06-68; 2 pages
  - Text of Secretary Rusk's Letter Submitting the NPT to the President for Transmittal to the Senate, 1968-07-02; 201 - NPT; 21 pages
  - NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY - Text of Parliamentary Question and Reply by Mr. Mulley in the House of Commons on the 8th July, 1968-07-09; 202 - Mr. Mully Statement; 3 pages
  - Text of President Johnson's Letter of Transmittal Forwarding the NPT to the Senate, 1968-07-09; 203 - President Johnson Statement; 17 pages
  - TEXT-RUSK STATEMENT ON NPT-SENATE FOREIGN RELATIONS COMMITTEE JULY 10, 1968, 1968-07-10; 204 - Rusk Statement; 5 pages
  - US Government's submission of the Non-Proliferation Treaty for the advice and consent to ratification of the United States Senate, 1968-07-15; 205 - Letter from Mr. Rusk; 19 pages
  - NPT Signatories, 1968-08-02; 206 - NPT Signatories; 1 page
  - British Government's intention to ratify the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons on 27 November, 1968-11-25; 207 - UK Ratification of Treaty; 1 page
  - L'état de la discussion sur la non prolifération - Memorandum, 1965-10-14; 10 - MEMO; 1 page
  - Le problème de la non-prolifération au lendemain de la visite de Lord Chalfont à l'OTAN (2 mars 1966), 1966-03-11; 33 - GAS(66)39; 4 pages
  - Note sur l'état des négociations de Genève sur la non-prolifération, 1966-07-22; 36 - DPA(66)240; 3 pages
  - Note sur l'état des négociations de Genève sur la non-proliferation, 1966-07-22; 37 - GAS(66)84; 3 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège Permanent, Paris (16e), le mercredi 19 octobre 1966 à 10h15, 1966-10-24; 46 - C-R(66)-55; 3 pages
  - Annexé (Diffusion restreinte) au prooès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue le mercredi 19 octobre 1966 à 10h15 - NON-PROLIFERATION, 1966-11-02; 48 - C-R(66)55 ANNEX; 16 pages
  - Procès-verbal d'une reunion du Conseil tenue au Siège Permanent, Paris (16e), le mardi 17 janvier 1967 â 10h15, 1967-01-30; 52 - C-R(67)2; 16 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la reunion du Conseil tenue au Siège Permanent, Paris (16e), le mercredi 1 févriier 1967 à 10h15, 1967-02-13; 59 - C-R(67)5; 26 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège Permanent, Paris (16e), le mercredi 8 févriier 1967 à 10h15, 1967-02-17; 64 - C-R(67)7; 27 pages
  - NON-DISSEMINATION DES ARMES NUCLEAIRES - COMMUNICATION DE LA DELEGATION DU PORTUGAL, 1967-02-13; 67 - PO(67)87; 3 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège Permanent, Paris (16e), le mercredi 22 févriier 1967 à 10h15, 1967-03-01; 74 - C-R(67)9; 18 pages
  - DÉCLARATION CANADIENNE SUR LA NON-PROLIFERATION, 1967-02-28; 75 - CA statement 28-02-1967; 3 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège Permanent, Paris (16e), le mercredi 6 septembre 1967 à 10h15, 1967-09-18; 109 - C-R(67)36; 26 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège Permanent, Paris (16e), le mercredi 20 septembre 1967 à 10h15, 1967-10-02; 112 - C-R(67)39; 31 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles, le mercredi 17 Janvier 1968 à 10h15, 1968-01-30; 149 - C-R(68)2; 22 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles, le jeudi 18 Janvier 1968 à 12h, 1968-02-01; 151 - C-R(68)3; 7 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles, le mardi 23 Janvier 1968 à 16h, 1968-02-07; 155 - C-R(68)4; 6 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles, le mercredi 31 Janvier 1968 à 10h15, 1968-02-19; 157 - C-R(68)7; 16 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles, le mercredi 7 février 1968 à 10h15, 1968-02-15; 159 - C-R(68)8; 5 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles, le mercredi 14 février 1968 à 16h, 1968-02-22; 163 - C-R(68)9; 14 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles, le mercredi 21 février 1968 à 10h15, 1968-03-04; 165 - C-R(68)10; 12 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles, le mercredi 28 février 1968 à 10h15, 1968-03-15; 168 - C-R(68)11; 22 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles, le mercredi 6 mars 1968 à 10h15, 1968-03-22; 174 - C-R(68)12; 25 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles, le mercredi 13 mars 1968 à 10h15 et 16h30, 1968-03-02; 178 - C-R(68)13; 18 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, à Bruxelles, le mercredi 20 mars 1968 à 10h15, 1968-04-05; 180 - C-R(68)14; 10 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles, le mercredi 10 avril 1968 à 10h15, 1968-04-25; 183 - C-R(68)18; 15 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles, le mercredi 24 avril 1968 à 10h15, 1968-05-07; 185 - C-R(68)19; 20 pages
  - Rapport, 1968-04-24; 186 - BE Del Letter No.3115; 10 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles, le mercredi 8 mai 1968 à 10h, 1968-05-21; 190 - C-R(68)22; 12 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles 39, le vendredi 7 juin 1968 à 10h15, 1968-07-15; 197 - C-R(68)28; 9 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège de l'OTAN, Bruxelles 39, le vendredi 20 juin 1968 à 10h15, 1968-07-12; 199 - C-R(68)33; 11 pages
- Related Committee documents on the NPT, 1963-1968; Volume 3; 36 Items; Subject File - Non-Proliferation Treaty
  Volume 3 of the collection is a curated collection of documents that were not included in the Political Affairs subject file in Volume 2. They include meeting minutes of the Political committee (AC/119). These documents were publicly disclosed as part of NATO’s yearly systematic declassification and public disclosure programme.
  - IRISH RESOLUTION ADOPTED ON 20th DECEMBER 1960, 1961-10-16; 1 - POL VII Nuclear Weapons Irish Resolution To UN 1961; 4 pages
  - Non-dissemination of nuclear weapons, 1963-04-26; 3 - GAS(63)84; 7 pages
  - SUMMARY OF SOVIET AIDE-MEMOIRE OF MAY 11, 1963, CONCERNING NON-TRANSFER OF NUCLEAR WEAPONS, 1963-06-05; 4 - US_Del_Soviet_Aide_Memoire_to_NAC_May15; 3 pages
  - Draft Irish Resolution on Non-dissemination, 1965-01-20; 5 - US_Del_Draft_Resolution_Ireland_Non-Dissemination_Nuclear_Weapons; 3 pages
  - Canadian Disarmament Non-Dissemination Treaty - DRAFT TREATY - PREVENTION OF THE WIDER DISSEMINATION OF NUCLEAR WEAPONS, 1965-07-05; 6 - Canadian proposal; 8 pages
  - CANADIAN AND UK DRAFT NON-DISSEMINATION TREATIES, 1965-07-19; 8 - DPA(65)401; 1 page
  - Comparative Table of Proposals in the Field of Non-Dissemination, 1965-07-26; 9 - Comparative_Table_Of_Proposals_Non-Dissemination; 8 pages
  - DRAFT TREATY ON NON-DISSEMINATION OF NUCLEAR WEAPONS, 1965-08-13; 10 - PO(65)437; 7 pages
  - STATEMENT BY MR. FOSTER BEFORE THE NATO COUNCIL ON NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY, 1965-09-17; 12 - US_Del_Statement_Foster_NAC; 5 pages
  - COMPARISON OF THE US AND USSR DRAFT TREATIES ON THE NON-DISSEMINATION OP NUCLEAR WEAPONS, 1965-10-18; 16 - PO(65)519; 4 pages
  - COMPARISON OF THE UNITED STATES AND SOVIET DRAFT TREATIES ON NON-DISSEMINATION OF NUCLEAR WEAPONS, 1965-10-19; 18 - PO(65)519_1; 2 pages
  - MEETING OF POLITICAL ADVISERS COMMITTEE 19TH OCTOBER 1965, 1965-10-20; 20 - DPA(65)509; 1 page
  - APAG Meeting in Portugal - 22nd-25th March, 1966, 1966-02-01; 21 - APAG(66)1; 4 pages
  - EXPLANATION OF CHANGES IN U.S. DRAFT NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY, 1966-02-16; 22 - US_Del_Changes_to_Draft_NPT; 4 pages
  - Delegation reaction regarding non-proliferation as possible subject for discussion in the Council., 1966-08-31; 24 - GAS(66)96; 2 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 21st September 1966 at 10.15 a.m., 1966-09-26; 25 - C-R(66)51; 5 pages
  - Restricted Annex to summary record of a meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 21st September 1966 at 10.15 a.m., 1966-09-30; 26 - C-R(66)51-ANNEX1; 10 pages
  - Addendum to Summary Record of Meeting of the Council held on 21st September, 1966, C-R(66)51 dated 26th September, 1966, 1966-09-27; 28 - C-R(66)51-ADD1; 1 page
  - COUNCIL DISCUSSION ON NON-PROLIFERATION, 1966-10-17; 29 - PO(66)486; 1 page
  - GERMAN MEMORANDUM ON THE PRESENT DISARMAMENT NEGOTIATIONS, 1966-10-20; 30 - 20-10-05_67_GE_Memo_on_NPT_Negotiations; 7 pages
  - Further comments on US draft Article III of a non-proliferation treaty concerning "safeguards", 1967-02-23; 32 - DPA(67)51; 1 page
  - U.S. Information Service Daily Radio Bulletin statements entitled "Stopping the Spread of Nuclear Weapons and a Non-Proileration Treaty", 1967-02-24; 33 - US_Del_Stopping_The_Spread_Of_Nuclear_Weapons; 7 pages
  - Norwegian Foreign Minister's statement to the Storting March 7, 1967 re. negotiations presently taking place in Geneva on an agreement on the non-proliferation of nuclear weapons, 1967-03-10; 34 - NOR_Foreign_Minister_Statement_NPT; 13 pages
  - Revised texts of the draft Non-Proliferation Treaty and of the Summary of Interpretations, 1967-04-03; 35 - US letter; 24 pages
  - STATEMENT OF GENERAL BURNS ON NPT - APRIL 12, 1967, 1967-04-12; 36 - Can_Del_Burns_Statement_NPT; 7 pages
  - The New Soviet Delegation Proposal on Safeguards, 1967-09-06; 37 - Memo_Analysis_Soviet_Del_Proposal_On_Safeguards; 7 pages
  - STATEMENT BY THE GERMAN PERMANENT REPRESENTATIVE AT THE COUNCIL MEETING ON 20 September 1967, 1967-09-20; 40 - GER_Del_Statement_NAC_Soviet_Proposition_Article3; 4 pages
  - United States Aide-Mémoire on the Status of the negotiations with the Soviet Union on Article III of the Non-Proliferation Treaty, 1967-11-13; 41 - US_Del_Aide_Memoire_Draft_Article3_NPT; 9 pages
  - Netherlands comments on the aide-memoires circulated by the UNITED STATES Permanent Representative on November 13 and November 23, 1967., 1967-12-04; 43 - NE_Del_Letter_7003; 3 pages
  - United States nuclear fuel supplies to Euratom for power and research reactors, 1967-12-20; 46 - US_Del_Nuclear_Supplies_Euratom; 1 page
  - Sentence to be added to first of three interpretative principles dealing with the nature of a EURATOM-IAEA agreement, 1968-01-19; 47 - Sentence_to_Add_US_Aide_Memoire_NAC_Nov13_Oct5_196745; 1 page
  - Statement by the U.K. Permanent Representative to the North Atlantic Council on 28 February 1968 on NPT SECURITY ASSURANCES, 1968-02-28; 48 - UK_Statememt_NAC_Security_Assurances; 2 pages
  - Draft of US Assurances Declaration, 1968-03-12; 49 - US_Del_Draft_US_Security_Assurances_NAC_March6; 3 pages
  - ESTABLISHMENT OF A DISARMAMENT AND ARMS CONTROL SECTION IN THE POLITICAL DIVISION OF THE SECRETARIAT, 1968-04-09; 50 - PO(68)209; 1 page
  - STAFFING OF PROPOSED DISARMAMENT AND ARMS CONTROL SECTION OF THE POLITICAL DIVISION OF THE INTERNATIONAL STAFF, 1968-06-17; 51 - PO(68)332; 1 page
  - Message from President Johnson to the ENDC, July 16, 1968, 1968-07-16; 52 - US_Del_Message_President_Johnson_to_ENDC_Jul16; 3 pages
  - Non-dissémination des armes nucléaires, 1963-04-26; 3 - GAS(63)84; 7 pages
  - Projets anglais et canadien de traité non dissémination, 1965-07-16; 7 - GAS(65)130; 9 pages
  - Version succincte de la déclaration faite par M. WILLOT à la séance du COMITE POLITIQUE du 12 OCTOBRE 1965, au sujet des projets américain et soviétique sur la non-dissemination nucléaire., 1965-10-12; 15 - BE_Del_Willot_to_Political_Committee; 5 pages
  - COMPARAISON DES PROJETS AMERIGAIN ET SOVIETIQUE DE TRAITE DE NON-DISSEMINATION DE L’ARME NUCLEAIRE, 1965-10-18; 17 - PO(65)519; 4 pages
  - COMPARAISON DES PROJETS AMERIGAIN ET SOVIETIQUE DE TRAITE DE NON-DISSEMINATION DE L’ARME NUCLEAIRE, 1965-10-19; 19 - PO(65)519_1; 2 pages
  - Le problème de la non-prolifération au lendemain de la visite de Lord Chalfont à l'OTAN (2 mars 1966), 1966-03-11; 23 - GAS(66)39; 4 pages
  - Procès-verbal de la réunion du Conseil tenue au Siège Permanent, Paris (16e), le mercredi 21 septembre 1966 à 10h15, 1966-09-26; 27 - C-R(66)51; 4 pages
  - Lettre P.15 No.50 de l'Ambassadeur Portugais sur position dans le débat qui a eu lieu au Conseil le 1er Février au sujet de la non-dissémination, 1967-02-07; 31 - PO_Del_Ambassador_NPT_NAC_1Feb; 2 pages
  - EXPOSÉ DE LA POSITION BELGE SUR LES DERNIERES PROPOSITtONS DE TEXTS DU TRAITE DE NON-DIFFUSION DES ARMES NUCLEAIRES, DEVANT LE CONSEIL ATLANTIQUE, le mercredi 20 septembre 1967, 1967-09-20; 39 - BEL_Del_Position_Soviet_Proposition_Article3_NPT; 5 pages
  - Déclaration gouvernementale belge publiée à l'occasion de la signature ce jour par la Belgique du Traité de Non Prolifération des Armes Nucléaires, 1968-08-20; 53 - BE_Del_Govt_Declaration_Upon_Signature_NPT; 3 pages